# **Chris Peter Francis**

College Station, Texas, United States chrispeterfrancis@tamu.edu 8329083500 chrispeterfrancis.com

### **SUMMARY**

Junior university student interested in cloud technologies, modern IT environments, and producing results at scale and with velocity. Experienced with several IT-stacks and development in various environments. Interested in joining Amazon Web Services' IT team to deliver projects and results.

### **EDUCATION**

B.S. Technology Management | Minor in Cybersecurity and Business | Texas A&M University | May 2022 | 4.0

### **SKILLS**

Development: HTML \ CSS \ JS, Python, Java, C, Lua

Operations: Unix, Windows, CLI, Bash, Troubleshooting, Ticketing Systems

Analytics: Excel, Access

General: Office Suite, Presentations, Documentation, Data Processing

#### **EXPERIENCE**

## IT Student Technician | Bush School of Government and Public Service | College Station, Texas | May 2020 - Present

- · Analyze, troubleshoot, and repair issues related to computers in a mixed operating system environment for over 100 end-users.
- · Customize, test, deploy and document over 80 software installation packages
- · Image nearly 300 computers utilizing computer deployment tools following specified procedures.

#### Guest Operations | Space Center Houston | Houston, Texas | October 2017 - August 2018

- · Greeted and interacted with over 300 local, national, and international guests daily.
- · Educated guests about the history of manned space flight and NASA endeavors.
- · Handled thousands of dollars daily using Point of Sale system.

#### **PROJECTS**

## Kaplan-Automate | Chi Psi Beta Fraternity Inc. | March 2020

- · Developed web scraping script using Python to retrieve over 1800 data points into self-maintained database.
- · Developed web automation script using Selenium to fill in information and reduce task time by 95%.
- $\cdot \ \, \text{Effectively raised $6,000 in funding for Mental Health Awareness with the application.} \\$

## Pelican-DevOps | January 2020

- · Worked with a pseudo Operations team to deploy a web application using Pelican and Git.
- · Configured cloud hosting for web application to implement small-scale CI/CD.

### DevOps Workshop Leader | Technology Management Society | 2021

- $\cdot \ \text{Aided students struggling with programming concepts in an operations environment.} \\$
- $\cdot \ \text{Taught importance and usage of several DevOps-focused tooling from Docker to Git.}$

#### Docker + Flask | March 2021

- · Developed a simple Flask API to handle URI requests for functions such as posting a message in Slack.
- · Containerized the application using Docker and used port mapping to access the application on localhost.
- · Connected the Flask Application to a Redis database, and connected the two containers using Docker Compose.
- $\cdot \ \mathsf{Composed\ application\ on\ an\ AWS\ EC2\ instance\ to\ demonstrate\ and\ understand\ public\ availability.}$

## RELEVANT COURSEWORK

Unix System Administration | Texas A&M University | 2021

DevOps and the Modern IT Team | Texas A&M University | 2021

Structured Programming in C | Texas A&M University | 2020

Programming in Python & Java | Texas A&M University | 2019

## INVOLVEMENT

# Digital Media, Service and Recruitment | Texas A&M University | Chi Psi Beta Service Fraternity Inc. | October 2018 - Present

- · Created over 20 multimedia presentations to display philanthropic, social and organization events.
- · Involved in raising over \$60,000 for various causes including disaster relief, mental health awareness, and disadvantaged schools.
- · Recruited new members and grew organization by 60%.